Guide to the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America Local 430 and Local 165 Records, 1961-1996 AIS.1997.06
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America Local 430 and Local 165 Records
1961-1996
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America. Local 165 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America. Local 430 (Wilkinsburg, Pa.)
AIS.1997.06
6.25 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
Local 430 of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America represented workers in Wilkinsburg, Pa., and Local 165 represented workers in Pittsburgh. This collection contains correspondence, minutes and convention proceedings of the union.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Zane Smigas in February 1997.
History
Local 430 of the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America was chartered on January 3, 1900, and represented workers in Wilkinsburg, Pa. Local 165 was a founding member of a western Pennsylvania carpenters district council and represents carpenters in the Pittsburgh area.
Previous Citation
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America Local 430 and Local 165 Records, 1961-1996, AIS.1997.06, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains correspondence, minutes and convention proceedings collected by Local 430. Also present is correspondence and research files from Local 165. There are also District Council records interspersed throughout the entirety of the collection.
Related Material
Projects of the Carpenters' District Council of Western Pennsylvania Record Books, 1938-1939, AIS.1969.19, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America Western Pennsylvania Regional District Council of Carpenters Records, Pittsburgh, Pa., 1887-1975, AIS.1996.12, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Arrangement
Series I. United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 430
Series II. United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 165
Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Wilkinsburg; Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Carpenters -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Wilkinsburg; Carpenters -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Labor; Proceedings (Reports); Minutes (Administrative records); Correspondence; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Wilkinsburg (Pa.); United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America. Local 165 (Pittsburgh, Pa.); United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America. Local 430 (Wilkinsburg, Pa.)
- United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 430, I.
  - Special Called Meeting Minutes, 1963-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1-8)
  - Outgoing Communications, 1962-1983 (Box 1, Folder 9-18)
  - Communications from Othre Locals, 1964-1992 (Box 1, Folder 19-23)
  - Carpenters Local 165 By-laws (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence from the Western Pennsylvania Regional District Council, Pittsburgh, PA, 1961-1985 (Box 1, Folder 25-36)
  - Carpenters District Council Annual Financial Reports, 1971-1982 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence from General President M.A. Hutcheson and W. Sidell, 1967-1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from General President W. Sidell, 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence from General President W. Konyha, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from General President P.J. Campbell, 1971-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of General Executive Board Meetings, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Carpenters Legislative Improvement Committee (CLIC-GO), 1964-1984 (Box 2, Folder 7-14)
  - Allegheny County Labor Council Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Allegheny County Labor Council Bulletins, 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Constitution of the Pennsylvania AFL-CIO, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Pennsylvania AFL-CIO News, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - AFL-CIO News, September 1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence from Pennsylvania AFL-CIO, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bond Reports, 1968-1978 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Tax Exempt Forms (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Information about Membership to the Warehouse Club (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "The Builders", July 1-August 5, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - AFL-CIO News, July 6-August 5, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Secretary's Order Book, Receipt Books, 1977-1985 (Box 2, Volume 1-15)
  - Synopsis Report of 66th Pennsylvania Carpenters State Convention (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Council of Carpenters, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "Changing Labor's Image: A Union Member's Guide" by Paul F. Clark (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Pennsylvania State Council Information Directory, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 66th Convention Agenda (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Worker's Right to Worker's Compensation" (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Union Yes" Stickers (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Report of the 33rd General Convention, St. Louis, October 2, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Report of the 35th General Convention, Toronto, October 6-10, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Report of the 36th General Convention, Atlantic City, October 7-11, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - National Conference, Grassroots Organizing Manual "The Future is in Our Hands", 1996 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Handwritten Notes from the 62nd PA Convention, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Financial Statement of All Locals, 1978-1991 (Box 3, Folder 13-26)
  - Password and Quarterly Circular, 1964-1990 (Box 3, Folder 27-31)
  - General Executive Board Minutes, 1964-1984 (Box 3, Folder 32-37)
  - Jurisdictional Decisions, 1964-1980 (Box 4, Folder 1-17)
  - Pennsylvania State Council, Secretary/Treasurer Reports and Executive Board Minutes, 1964-1980 (Box 4, Folder 18-34)
  - State Council News, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America, Local 165, II.
  - Minute Books, 1979-1996 (Box 4, Volume 1-2)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1970-1989 (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence from Carpenters District Council of Western Pennsylvania, 1970-1975, 1988-1991 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence from National Office, 1962-1975, 1984-1991 (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
  - Correspondence from Carpenters Joint Apprenticeship Committee, 1984-1991 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence from Other Union Locals, 1985-1990 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Contingent Fund (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - John Kopay, Election Protest (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Union Privilege Legal Service (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Pennsylvania State Council of Carpenters, "Plane Talk" (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Pennsylvania State Council of Carpenters, "State Wide Alerts" (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Pennsylvania State Council of Carpenters, General Executive Board Minutes (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Pennsylvania State Council of Carpenters, Financial Statements (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Directory of Contractors (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Banquet Menus and Tickets (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence from US and State Senates (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Memos to Board of Governors, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Application for Membership, 1985-1990 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Central Blood Bank Information and Newsletter (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Doctor's Certificates and Sick Notes, 1984-1992 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Invoices and Receipts, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Labor Organization's Annual Report LM-3, 1970-1975 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity, 1978-1987 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Tax Forms (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Pennsylvania AFL-CIO (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - United Brotherhood of Carpenters National Health and Safety Fund, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - By-laws (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - District Council By-laws, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Financial Statements, 1984-1989 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Bills (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Pittsburgh Politics (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Change of Address (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 37)